Stephen Agyei

St. Joseph's College of Education P. O. Box 15, Bechem

Mobile: 024 1179264/ 0242140213 Email: namponsem19@gmail.com

Profile

Flexible, organized and well-rounded enthusiastic educator with more than 10 years ofteaching expertise with unique ability to explain concepts in Physics in aneasily understandable manner.

Talent for employing unique teaching strategies to effectively engage all students andfoster a fun and fascinating learning environment.

Active team member who effectively collaborates with all levels of staff members andshares best practices.

Expertise

- Effective research, analytical and presentation techniques.
- Technology integration.
- Good organizational skills and perfectly able to work under stress.
- Emphasizing the relevance of class material to the world beyond the classroom.
- Excellent team teaching approach.

Academic Qualification

June 2014 – August 2016 Diploma in Education

University of Education Winneba- Kumasi Campus

<u>Subjects:</u> Philosophical and Sociological Foundation of Education, Development of Education in Ghana, School Organization and Management, Guidance and Counselling, Introduction to Special Education, Academic writing, Project Work, On and Off – Campus Teaching Practice, Educational Research, Educational Psychology, Special Education, English Grammar, Measurement, Evaluation and Statistics.etc.

September 2009 – June 2014

MPhil Materials Science

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology, Kumasi, Ghana.

<u>Core subjects</u>: Mathematical Methods for Physics, Statistical Physics, Analytical and Quantative methods in Materials Science, Advanced Quantum Mechanics, Metallic Materials, Theory Of Fields, Ceramics and Composites, Quantum Mechanics, Polymeric Materials, Human Resource Management, Leadership and Organizational Behaviour, Numerical Methods and Statistics, Advanced Programming,

<u>Special Study</u>: Thesis (Tensile Strength, Microhardness, and Corrossion Studiesof Aluminium and Galvanized Roofing sheets used in Ghana.)

September 1997 – March 2001

BSc. Physics, Second Class Honours

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology, Kumasi, Ghana.

<u>Core Subjects:</u> Information Technology, Elements of Programming, Programming with Fortran, Introduction to Computers, Communication Skills, Nuclear Physics, Quantum Mechanics, Classical Mechanics, Wave and Vibrations, Electricity and Magnetism, Experimental Physics, Mathematics for Physics, Physical Chemistry, Properties of Matter, Heat and Thermodynamics, Electronics, Solid State Physics, Basic Instrumentation, Statistical Mechanics, Electromagnetic Theory, Optics, Atomic Physics, Spectroscopy.

<u>Optional Subjects:</u> Medical Physics, Optoelectronics, Environmental Studies, French for Communication, Introduction to Management, Introductory Economics.

Special Study: Thesis (Radioactive Environmental Pollution of Water bodies in Ashanti Region.)

September 1993 – 1995 June

GCE 'A' Levels in Physics, Mathematics, Chemistry and General Paper.

Ghana Secondary Technical School, Takoradi

September 1988 – June 1993

GCE 'O' Levels in Physics, Mathematics, Chemistry, English Language, Economics, Additional Mathematics, Biology and Metal Technology.

Ghana Secondary Technical School, Takoradi

Work History

September 2014 – Present

Physics Tutor/ Head of Science Department

St. Joseph's College of Education, Bechem

September 2010 – present

Physics Tutor/ Assistant Examiner

University of Cape Coast, College of Distance Education KSTS Center, Kumasi.

September 2006 – September 2014

Physics Teacher/ Head of Physics Department Kumasi Wesley Girl's Senior High School

September 2002 – August 2006

Physics Teacher / Form Master.

Archbishop Porter Girls' Secondary School, Takoradi,

March 2001–December 2002

Physics Tutor, Takoradi Secondary School (Through the National Service Scheme)

March 1996 - December 1996

Physics Tutor, Juabeso Secondary School (Through the National Service Scheme)

Workshops and Seminars Attended

 $6^{th}-10^{th}\,$ May, 2019 @ AngeHill Hotel, East Legon - Accra

Theme: Gender – Responsive e –learning (e – based teaching and learning and e – assessment) in Science and Mathematics.

Organized by UNESCO

15th – 19th August 2017 @ M Plaza Hotel, Accra

Theme: Gender – Responsive e – learning content development and e–assessment for STEM Subjects Organized by UNESCO

19th – 23rd November, 2018 @ Royal Beulah Hotel, Accra

Theme: Objective of the workshop was to 'introduce current STEM pedagogies and curriculum ideas for better preparing STEM teachers in Ghana and Ethiopia to attract and support girls in the field of studies.

Organized by UNESCO

2017 – Present

Professional Development Programme on Assessing Trainee Teachers

Organized by T-TEL and St. Joseph College of Education

August 2007

Capacity Building for Science and Mathematics Teachers on the theme,' **Science, Technology and Mathematics Education – The Teacher Factor'**

Organized by Kumasi Wesley Girls School

Industrial Attachment

August 2000 - October 2000Ghana Telecom (Madina Exchange, Accra)

August 1999 - October 1999Ghana Telecom (Madina Exchange, Accra)

Position Held: Fault Testing Officer Mngr.

- practical skills
- liaison with clients
- working to tight deadline, for long and odd hours
- working under pressure and with little supervision

REFERENCES

Prof. S. K. Danour Head, Physics Department KNUST Matthew Addai, Principal, St. Joseph College of Education

Bechem

Dr. Kwakye Awuah

Lecturer,

Physics Department

KNUST.